Privacy PolicyLast updated: 17/10/2022

About this Policy

For all of us at Securus Software Limited, the protection of personal data is of paramountimportance and we go to great lengths to ensure that we collect and use personal data lawfullyand only for specific purposes.

This Policy applies to any personal data which we process about job applicants and pastemployees, personnel of customers, suppliers, partners and other organisations who we workwith as part of our business operations, visitors to our website and users of our products andservices (each of which we refer to in this Policy as “data subject” or “you”).

In this Policy we explain the things which we think are important for you to know about thepersonal data we collect from you such as who we are, how we use your data, how we protectyour data and who we may share your data with. We also explain the rights you have in relationto your personal data which we hold. Finally, there’s a bit about cookies – what they are andhow to get rid of them if you don’t want them. If you have any questions relating to how wehandle your personal data, please write or email us at the contact address set out below.

This Policy does not cover the links within our website linking to other websites. We encourageyou to read the privacy statements of the other websites you visit.

Securus Software Limited is committed to keeping information provided by you confidentialand we shall always be transparent with you about how we are using your details to complywith the GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation).

About us

Securus Software Limited (“Securus”) is a limited company established in England withcompany registration number 04613837.Our registered address is at LAN2LAN House, BrookWay, Leatherhead, Surrey, KT22 7NA and our primary business address is at LAN2LANHouse, Brook Way, Leatherhead, Surrey, KT22 7NA. We are registered with the InformationCommissioners Office under registration number Z1647176.

We act as both a data controller and a data processor under the GDPR.

We are a data controller in relation to your personal data because we decide what yourpersonal data can be used for and how the personal data is processed. We collect yourpersonal data in the legitimate interests of carrying out business with the organisation youwork for or represent.

We are a data processor in the context of providing Customers, such as schools and colleges,with our Securus software solutions, and the Customer is the data controller.

Where we process personal data on behalf of another company or organisation, we will bedoing so as a data processor and our processing will be governed by a contract which we willhave with the data controller who will have their own separate privacy notice which will apply.

About your personal data

The personal data we collect, the purpose(s) we use it for and the lawful basis we hold it willvary depending on the category of the person it relates to. To help explain this, we have setout these separate categories as follows:

Customer Personnel

What personal data we collect

We may collect your personal data when you correspond with us on behalf of the company ororganisation that you work for.

The personal data we collect will typically include your name, the name and address of thecompany or organisation you work for, your business telephone number, your mobiletelephone number if you provide it and your company or organisation email address.

How we use your personal data

We will use your personal data only to correspond with you in the course of businessconducted between us and the organisation you work for or represent. This may includenotifying you about existing products and services which we provide to your organisation,informing you about new products and services which we think your organisation may beinterested in, for billing and payment and also to provide your organisation with timelycustomer support.

The lawful basis for our collection and use of the personal data

Our processing of this personal data is necessary for the purposes of our legitimate interestsin carrying out business with the organisation which you work for or represent and tocorrespond with you.

Supplier Personnel

What personal data we collect

We may collect your personal data when you correspond with us on behalf of the company ororganisation that you work for.

The personal data we collect will typically include your name, the name and address of thecompany or organisation you work for, your business telephone number, your mobiletelephone number if you provide it and your company or organisation email address.

How we use your personal data

We will use your personal data only to correspond with you in the course of businessconducted between us and the organisation you work for or represent. This may includecontacting you in connection with existing products and services which your organisationprovides to us, for billing and payment, for support and in response to your enquiries.

The lawful basis for our collection and use of the personal data

Our processing of this personal data is necessary for the purposes of our legitimate interestsin carrying out business with the organisation which you work for or represent and tocorrespond with you.

Prospective Customers

What personal data we collect

We may collect your personal data in connection with marketing events, sales opportunitiesor in response to requests for information which you have made to us.

The personal data we collect will typically include your name, the name and address of thecompany or organisation you work for, your business telephone number, your mobiletelephone number if you provide it and your company or organisation email address.

How we use your personal data

We will use your personal data only to correspond with you in connection with our provisionof products and/or services to the organisation you work for or represent.

The lawful basis for our collection and use of the personal data

Our processing of this personal data is necessary for the purposes of our legitimate interestsin offering products and/or services to the organisation which you work for or represent and tocorrespond with you.

Visitors to our website

What personal data we collect

When you visit our website, we may collect your personal information where you submit aform containing your personal data or where the website helps you send an email to us.

The personal data we collect will typically includes your name (“First Name”, “Last Name”),job title (“Position”), the company or organisation you work for (“Establishment Name”), emailaddress (“Email”) and the information contained in any correspondence with you.

How we use your personal data

We will use your personal data only for the purpose of communicating with you in response toyour enquiries.

The lawful basis for our collection and use of the personal data

Our processing of this personal data is necessary for the purposes of our legitimate interestsin providing our products and/or services to you.

Users of our Software

What personal data we collect

Providing the Securus software and services includes collecting the Customer issuedcomputer user names, Customer names, Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type,machine model and webpages viewed and their associated data.

How we use your personal data

Information is monitored and sorted based on policy criteria provided by the Customer, for thepurpose of identifying for the Customer any at-risk computer behaviour. This is used to createrisk notifications to the nominated Customer users of the software.

The lawful basis for our collection and use of the personal data

This information is vital to identify which user, website or similar data specifically poses a risk,or is at risk.

Our safekeeping of your data

The Securus cloud portal server and data storage components are hosted in the Digital OceanLON1 datacentre based in the United Kingdom, which is certified to ISO 9001, the internationalStandard for Quality Management and ISO/IEC 27001, the internationally recognised standardfor Information Security.

We use Transport Layer Security (TLS) version 1.2 or higher along with AES encryption toprovide communications security and ensure all traffic between the clients and the servers istransferred securely.

We have implemented all appropriate technical, organisational and security procedures toprotect your personal data from unauthorised access or from accidental loss or corruption,including encryption of data in transit, firewalls and additional measures to protect theconfidentiality, availability, and integrity of your data, and in alignment with requirements ofapplicable regulation. These measures include restricting physical access to locations wherepersonal data is held and using access controls and firewalls to prevent unauthorised accessto our systems.

We recommend that you also take steps to safeguard your personal data against the risk ofunauthorised access or accidental loss or corruption. Where we provide you with password-restricted access to our website, software and/or services, it is your responsibility to use astrong password and to keep it private. We employ robust access controls to ensure that alldata is secured against unauthorised access. The credentials attached to your access willonly allow you to view data relevant to you.

Should we become aware of any security incident we have procedures in place to review andassess whether this will result in a personal data breach and if this is the case we will notifyyou and the appropriate regulator of any breach in accordance with our statutory obligations.

Who we may disclose your personal data to

Except as set out above and save for the following exceptions, we will not disclose yourpersonal information to any third party.

• We may disclose your personal data to our group companies.

• We will disclose your personal data to law enforcement agencies or regulatory bodiesif we are required to do so by law.

• We will disclose your personal data to our third party service providers to allow themto provide Securus Software features on our behalf, with agreement from all partiesconcerned.

• We may disclose your personal details to a third party in connection with the sale ormerger of our business.

• We may employ other companies to provide services for us, including for example,processing of payments and freight which services are necessary in order for us to beable to provide our services to you. These companies have access to the personalinformation needed to perform their functions and not for any other purposes and arebound by confidentiality agreements not to disclose any information for any otherpurpose.

If at any time we wish to disclose your personal data in circumstances other than those above,we will always obtain your express consent before doing so.

We store your personal details in the United Kingdom and we will not be transferring your dataoutside the European Union.

How long we keep your personal data

Unless we provide for a specific duration in the categories set out above, we will keep yourpersonal data for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Policy after whichtime we will either delete your personal data or remove all personal identifiers from the dataso that it has become anonymous.

International data transfers

We do not transfer your personal data to any country outside the EU.

Cookies

What is a cookie? A cookie is a text string of information that a website transfers to the cookiefile of the browser on your device so that the website can remember who you are. A cookiewill typically contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, the "lifetime" ofthe cookie, and a value, usually a randomly generated unique number.

We may use cookies to record information about how you access our website for statisticssolely for us and. To the extent that these cookies contain personally identifying data, this willbe limited to IP addresses only. You can choose not to accept cookies by setting thepreferences on your internet browser. If you do not accept cookies from us, this may impair orprevent some or all of the services which we provide to you.

To find out more about cookies, what they are used for and how to remove them, please visitthe Interactive Advertising Bureau Europe’s website athttp://www.allaboutcookies.org/cookies/

Communications

We may use your Personal Information to contact you with newsletters, marketing orpromotional materials and other information via email (email newsletters) or other methods.The information we collect and store relating to you is primarily used to enable us to provideour services to you. We may use the information for the following purposes:

• To provide you with information relating to our products or services.

• To provide information on other products and services which we feel may be oflegitimate interest to you

• To meet our contractual commitments to you.

• To notify you about any changes to our website, such as improvements orservice/product changes, that may affect the service we provide.

You will have the option to “opt out” or “unsubscribe” of receiving newsletters, marketing orpromotional materials and other communications at any time and each time you receiveelectronic marketing information from us, you have the option to decline to receive furtherinformation from us. Communications frequently include essential information regarding yourservice and updates that are needed in order to use the product to its fullest capacity.

In the event that you wish your personal information to be removed from our databases thenplease write to us at our registered office shown on the “Contact” page of our website or emailadmin@securus-software.com.

Changes to This Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy is effective as of 17/05/2018 and will remain in effect except with respectto any changes in its provisions in the future, which will be in effect immediately after beingposted on this page. The “last updated” date at the top of this policy indicates when it waslast revised. We reserve the right to update or change our Privacy Policy at any time andyou should check this Privacy Policy periodically.

Your continued use of the Service after we post any modifications to the Privacy Policy onthis page will constitute your acknowledgment of the modifications and your consent to abideand be bound by the modified Privacy Policy. If we make any material changes to thisPrivacy Policy, we will notify you either through the email address you have provided us, orby placing a prominent notice on our website.

Contact Us

Your rights in relation to your personal data

As a data subject, the law provides you with certain rights in relation to your personal datawhich we hold. You have the right to request the following: (1) Access to your personal dataand information about why we hold it and who we can disclose it to; (2) Correction of yourpersonal data if it is inaccurate, incomplete or out of date; (3) Deletion of your personal data(for example where you withdraw consent to our processing of your personal data or if youobject to our processing and we have no overriding legitimate interest to continue to processyour data); (4) Stopping the processing of your personal data for certain purposes such asdirect marketing; (5) To receive your personal data in a commonly used machine-readableformat or have this data sent to your designated recipient; and (6) To object to automaticdecision making and profiling based on your personal data. Where we rely on your consent toprocess your personal data, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time.

To request a copy of your personal data or to make any other request outlined above, pleasecontact our Data Protection Officer by emailing admin@securus-software.com or by post atthe contact details given above. To safeguard the personal data we hold, we need to confirmyour identity before we can take action following a request made under this section.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us.
